* *
**
- Whoo! Yeah!
- 呼！是的！
Uh-huh, uh-huh!
嗯嗯嗯！
Uh-huh!
嗯嗯！
Ooh!
哦！
* *
**
Uh-huh!
嗯嗯！
- SpongeBob, I need--
-海绵宝宝，我需要--
Whoa.
Sponge--
哇哦。
海绵 -
- Patty, no!
- 帕蒂，不！
- Oh, I can't quite reach it.
- 哦，我不太够得着。
Listen here, boy-o!
听着，小伙子！
As long as that patty's stuck
in the chimney,
只要那个馅饼卡住了
在烟囱里，
it's money outta me pocket!
这是我口袋里的钱！
You're gonna have to
go up there
你将不得不
上去那里
and fish it out.
- Oh, boy!
然后把它捞出来。
- 哦，孩子！
Looks like I'm taking my career
to new heights.
看来我要放弃我的职业生涯了
达到新的高度。
Meep!
米普！
All right, chimney,
好吧，烟囱，
prepare to be swept.
准备被横扫。
* *
**
There you are!
你在那里！
Good as new!
完好如新！
crowd:
人群：
Hold on, patty!
坚持住，帕蒂！
I've got you!
我有你！
No!
不！
- Okay, SpongeBob.
- 好吧，海绵宝宝。
Time to come back down
and get to work
是时候回来了
并开始工作
so I can garnish your wages
for wasting that patty!
这样我就可以扣押你的工资
浪费那个馅饼！
* *
**
- Oh, you know,
I think I'll just
- 哦，你知道，
我想我只会
stay up here a while.
在这里呆一会儿。
It's such a nice day, and all.
这真是美好的一天，等等。
- Nonsense, boy-o.
Just climb on down!
- 废话，小伙子。
就这样爬下去吧！
No, I'm good!
不，我很好！
- SpongeBob,
- 海绵宝宝，
I order you to come down here
immediately!
我命令你到这里来
立即！
- Don't worry,
I'll get him down
- 别担心，
我会把他弄下来
with my newest invention:
Extend-O-Boots.
我的最新发明：
延长 O 形靴。
I just press this button, and...
我只要按下这个按钮，然后...
Whoa!
哇！
- Sorry, I haven't worked out
all the kinks yet.
- 抱歉，我还没练好
所有的问题还没有解决。
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa-oh-oh!
哇哇哇！
哇哦哦！
- Whoa!
- What the--
- 哇！
- 什么是--
- So, uh...
- 那么，呃...
anybody else got an idea?
还有其他人有想法吗？
- It's okay, I got him!
- 没关系，我找到他了！
- Hey, SpongeBob.
- 嘿，海绵宝宝。
Whatcha doing wa
娃在做什么
Let's climb down now.
我们现在就爬下去吧。
Aw, thanks, Patrick,
but you go on ahead.
噢，谢谢，帕特里克，
但你继续前进。
I just can't do it.
我就是做不到。
It's too far down!
太差了！
- Aw, don't worry, SpongeBob.
- 噢，别担心，海绵宝宝。
Your old pal Patrick has
another plan
你的老朋友帕特里克有
另一个计划
to get you off this roof.
让你离开这个屋顶。
Sure.
Just do what I do.
当然。
就做我做的事吧。
Hm...
嗯...
Ow!
噢！
- Uh, never mind, Patrick.
I think I'll stay where I am.
- 呃，没关系，帕特里克。
我想我会留在原地。
[crowd chattering
disapprovingly]
[众人议论纷纷
不以为然地]
Hey, it's not so bad up here.
嘿，这里没那么糟糕。
Pretty great, really.
非常棒，真的。
I sure do miss my friends,
though.
我确实很想念我的朋友们
不过。
Hey, maybe I can see them
from up here.
嘿，也许我可以看到他们
从这里。
Ooh, looks like
Squidward has a date.
哦哦，看起来像
章鱼哥有个约会。
Good for him.
It can be so tough
对他有好处。
它可以如此艰难
to put yourself out there.
把自己放在那里。
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
Poor Squidward.
可怜的章鱼哥。
He's all alone!
他孤身一人！
Ah!
啊!
Don't worry, friend.
I'm here for you.
别担心，朋友。
我在这里等你。
Hm?
Oh!
嗯？
哦！
Oh!
Oh, that feels good.
哦！
哦，感觉很好。
Huh?!
啊？！
- Hmm, maybe he's hungry.
- 嗯，也许他饿了。
* *
**
- Come on, Squidward!
Eat your...
- 来吧，章鱼哥！
吃你的...
- Ow, hand cramp!
- 哎呀，手抽筋了！
Ow-ow-ow-ow!
噢-噢-噢-噢！
* *
**
- Guess he wasn't hungry
after all.
- 我猜他不饿
毕竟。
- I guess there's nothing left
to do but go to sleep.
-我想已经什么都没有剩下了
要做的事情就是去睡觉。
Oh, I wish I had my bed...
哦，我希望我有一张床......
Hey, that gives me an idea.
嘿，这给了我一个主意。
* *
**
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
* *
**
Perfect.
完美的。
Good night...
晚安...
nobody.
没有人。
- Yoo-hoo, SpongeBob!
- 哟吼，海绵宝宝！
Time to wake up!
- Oh, morning, Mr. Krabs.
是时候醒来了！
- 哦，早上好，蟹老板。
I've come up with a solution
我想出了一个解决方案
for your little roof problem,
boy-o!
对于你的屋顶小问题，
男孩哦！
- Now you can cook even if
you can't get back down.
- 现在你可以做饭了，即使
你不能再下来了。
Oh, thank you, Mr. Krabs.
哦，谢谢你，蟹老板。
- Now start making me money!
- 现在开始赚钱！
- Oh, Grilly, I thought
I'd never see you again!
-哦，格里利，我想
我再也见不到你了！
Something still doesn't feel
right, though.
仍然感觉不到什么
是的，不过。
* *
**
[drill whirring,
SpongeBob grunting]
[钻头呼呼地响，
海绵宝宝咕哝]
* *
**
Perfect!
Just like my old kitchen.
完美的！
就像我的旧厨房一样。
* *
**
I'm ready!
我准备好了！
Squidward, order's up!
章鱼哥，命令已定！
Oh, yeah.
I'm stuck up on this roof.
哦，是的。
我被困在这个屋顶上了。
Hmm...how do I get
these patties
嗯...我怎样才能得到
这些肉饼
down to the customers?
到客户？
Eureka!
尤里卡！
- We paid for patties, Krabs!
- 蟹蟹们，我们付了肉饼的钱！
Where's our food?
- Hey, calm down, everyone.
我们的食物在哪里？
- 嘿，大家冷静点。
I'm sure we can figure
something out
我相信我们能想到
出了点什么
that doesn't involve violence
or...refunds.
不涉及暴力
或...退款。
- Hey, outside!
It's raining Krabby Patties!
- 嘿，外面！
蟹肉饼下雨了！
Squidward and Krabs: Huh?
章鱼哥和蟹蟹：啊？
- Safe!
- 安全的！
- I'll take one Krabby Patty
and a drink, please.
- 我要一份蟹肉饼
请喝一杯。
I said, "And a drink!"
我说：“还有一杯饮料！”
These are cold!
这些很冷！
I paid for a hot meal.
我付了一顿热饭的钱。
all: Yeah!
全体：是啊！
- Maybe if we go up there,
we can get 'em fresh!
-也许如果我们去那里的话
我们可以让它们新鲜！
To the roof!
all: Yeah!
到屋顶！
全体：是啊！
- Whoa!
I better make more room up here.
- 哇！
我最好在这里腾出更多空间。
- You know, boy-o,
- 你知道，男孩，
at first I just thought
you were being a lily-livered,
起初我只是想
你本来就是百合花，
spineless, cry-baby,
scaredy-pants,
没有骨气，爱哭鬼，
吓人的裤子，
invertebrate loser.
无脊椎动物的失败者。
- But this rooftop restaurant
of yours
- 但这家屋顶餐厅
你的
really has me business booming!
真是让我生意兴隆啊！
- Wish you could've
- 但愿你能
talked Squidward into
joining us up here.
说服章鱼哥
加入我们吧。
Finally, this place
has some class.
最后，这个地方
有一些课。
I might actually enjoy
working here now.
我可能真的很喜欢
现在在这里工作。
- Ten more patties, SpongeBob!
- 还有十块肉饼，海绵宝宝！
- You got it, Mr. K.
- 你明白了，K先生。
- Aw...
- 噢...
- No, no--me money!
- 不，不——我的钱！
- Being outside is awful!
- 呆在外面太糟糕了！
* *
**
But we're under--
但我们正处于——
- Wait, wait, don't go!
- 等等，等等，别走！
A little wind
有一点风
never hurt anyone!
永远不要伤害任何人！
- Whoa, whoa!
- 哇，哇！
Ow!
噢！
SpongeBob, we're losing 'em.
Do something!
海绵宝宝，我们正在失去他们。
做点什么吧！
- Aye-aye, sir!
- 是啊，先生！
* *
**
- It's beautiful, boy-o!
- 很漂亮，男孩！
- Yeah, it's pretty nice,
but now that we're not outside,
- 是的，这很漂亮，
但现在我们不在外面
I'm starting to get bored.
- Yeah, so...
我开始感到无聊了。
- 是的，所以...
- Wait!
You can't be bored
- 等待！
你不能感到无聊
when there's dancing!
当有跳舞的时候！
[electronic dance
music playing]
[电子舞曲
音乐播放]
Whoo!
呼！
[grunting and shouting
rhythmically]
[咕哝和喊叫
有节奏地]
* *
**
- He's right!
- 他是对的！
* *
**
- Hooray!
We're not on the roof anymore.
- 万岁！
我们不再在屋顶上了。
- You know, after all
that dancing
- 毕竟你知道
那个跳舞
and partying today,
tomorrow's gonna feel
今天还有聚会，
明天会感觉
like starting a new business!
- And I'm looking forward
就像开始一项新业务一样！
- 我很期待
to getting in
on the ground floor with you!
进入
和你一起在一楼！
Time to go home already?
已经到回家的时间了吗？
Ow.
噢。
* *
**